第三樓字幕網www.disanlou.org
字幕僅供翻譯交流使用, 禁止用於商業用途
哈羅?
Hello?
救救我
Hey! Hey! Help me!
去帶他出來
Go get him.
你的第一天,菜鳥
Day one, Greenie.
該起床了
Rise and shine.
我覺得他應該幹雜活手
He looks like a slopper to me.
我在廚房需要幫忙
I could use some help in the kitchen.
有人要落跑了
Hey, we got a runner!
好好看清楚吧
Take it all in.
(移 動 迷 宮)
交給你了
He's all yours.
菜鳥,你好
Hey there, Green Bean.
不要再落跑了,好嗎?
You're not gonna run again. Okay?
很好
Good.
我叫艾爾比
My name is Alby.
你能聊聊自己嗎?你是誰?
Can you tell me anything about yourself? Who you are?
打哪來的?什麼都行
Where you came from? Anything at all.
不行
No.
你能告訴我你的名字嗎?
Can you tell me your name?
我什麼都想不起來
I, uh, I can't remember anything.
- 我為何什麼都不記得?  - 沒關係
- Why can't I remember anything?   - It's okay.
放鬆
Hey, relax.
Relax.
這很正常
It's normal.
我們全都經歷過
It happens to us all.
你一兩天后會想起你的名字的
You'll get your name back in a day or two.
他們只讓我們記得這件事
It's the one thing they let us keep.
這是什麼地方?
What is this place?
我帶你去看看吧
Let me show you.
我們在這裡吃飯
We eat here.
在這裡睡覺
We sleep here.
我們自己種食物跟搭棚子
We grow our own food. We build our own shelter.
不管我們需要什麼,箱子都會提供
Whatever we need, the Box provides.
其餘就靠我們自己了
The rest is up to us.
箱子?
The Box?
對,它一個月會上來一次
Yeah. It's sent up once a month
送物資跟一個新菜鳥來
with fresh supplies and a new Greenie.
這個月是你
This month that's you.
恭喜了
Congratulations.
送上來?誰把我們帶到這裡的?
Sent up? By who, though? Who put us here?
沒有人知道
That, we don't know.
艾爾比,你沒事吧?
Hey, are you all right, Alby? A-ha!
菜鳥,這是紐特
Green Bean, meet Newt.
我不在的時候就由他負責
When I'm not around, he's in charge.
還好你永遠都在
Well, it's a good thing you're always around then.
你剛剛跑得可真快
That was some dash you made earlier.
我一度還以為你可以當飛毛腿
For a second, I thought you had the chops to be a runner...
直到你臉栽到地上
...till you face-planted.
好精彩
That was great.
等等,飛毛腿?
Wait, a "runner"?
紐特,幫我一個忙,去找查克
Newt, do me a favor. Go find Chuck.
- 好  - 謝了
- All right.   - Thanks.
抱歉,參觀時間很趕
Look, I'm sorry to rush this.
你上來得有點晚,我們又有很多事要做
You came up a little late, and there's a lot to do.
今晚有特別的計畫
We got something special planned tonight.
對,你晚點就知道了
Yeah. You'll see.
希望你沒有懼高症
I hope you're not afraid of heights.
上來吧,快
Let's go. Come on.
全部就這麼大了
This is all we got.
我們為此辛苦打拚
We've worked hard for it.
如果你尊重這個地方
If you respect this place...
你我就能相安無事
you and I will get along just fine.
外面是什麼?
What's out there?
我們只有三條規矩
We only have three rules.
第一,做好你的分內事
First, do your part.
我們沒空理白吃白喝的人
No time for any freeloaders.
第二,不能傷害幽地鬥士
Second, never harm another Glader.
大家要互相信任才能成功
None of this works unless we have trust.
最重要的是
Most importantly...
千萬別到那些牆後面
never go beyond those walls.
菜鳥,懂嗎?
Do you understand me, Greenie?
艾爾比
Hey, Alby!
查克,你跑去哪了?
Hey, Chuck. Where you been, man?
大家都一樣
It's basically the same story for all of us.
我們在箱子裡醒來,艾爾比帶我們參觀
We wake up in the Box, Alby gives us the tour...
然後我們就在這裡了
then here we are.
別擔心
Don't worry.
你已經比我表現好了
You're already doing better than I did.
他們把我從大籠子拖出來時
I clunked my pants three times
我嚇到銼屎三次
before they got me out of the pit.
不會吧
No, come on.
你要去哪?
Dude, where are you going?
我只是想看看
I just wanna see.
你愛怎麼看都行
You can look around all you want
但你最好不要過去
but you better not go out there.
為什麼?那裡有什麼?
Why not? What's through there?
不知道,我只知道他們告訴我的事
I don't know. I just know what I'm told.
我們不能離開
And we're not supposed to leave.
查克,這是新來的菜鳥嗎?
Hey, Chuck. New Greenie, huh?
升格的感覺怎麼樣?
How does it feel to be promoted?
本,感覺很贊
Feels great, Ben.
我以為沒人能離開
I thought no one was allowed to leave.
我是說我們不能離開
I said we're not allowed to leave.
他們是飛毛腿,不一樣
They're different, they're runners.
他們比別人都瞭解迷宮
They know more about the maze than anyone.
等等,什麼?
Wait, what?
什麼?
What?
什麼?你剛剛說迷宮?
What? You just said "maze."
我有嗎?
I did?
對
Yeah.
你要去哪?你在幹嘛?
Where are you going? What are you doing?
我只是想看一下
I'm just gonna take a look.
我跟你說過你不行了
I told you, you can't.
沒人能離開,尤其不是現在
No one leaves, especially not now.
不安全
It's not safe.
好,我不會進去
Okay, all right, I'm not gonna go.
菜鳥,我們不能再這樣碰面了
We gotta stop meeting like this, Greenie.
- 放開我  - 好了,冷靜點
- Get off me!   - All right! Calm, calm, calm.
- 別碰我  - 不要激動
- Don't touch me!   - Whoa! Take it easy!
放輕鬆
Just relax.
你們有什麼毛病?
What the hell is wrong with you guys?
冷靜下來,好嗎?
Just calm down, all right?
不,好吧,你們為什麼不告訴我外面是什麼
No, okay? Why won't you tell me what's out there?
我們只是想保護你,這是為了你好
We're just trying to protect you. It's for your own good.
你們不能把我關在這裡
You guys can't just keep me here.
- 我不能讓你走  - 為什麼不行?
- I can't let you leave.   - Why not?
什麼東西?
What the hell?
下次,我會讓你走的
Next time, I'm gonna let you leave.
歡迎來到迷宮幽地
Welcome to the Glade.
點火吧
Light him up!
菜鳥,第一天還真精彩
Hell of a first day, Greenie.
來
Here.
來點烈的吧
Put some hair on your chest.
天啊,這是什麼?
Oh, my God! What is that?
我不知道
I don't even know.
這是蓋裡的配方
It's Gally's recipe.
商業機密
It's a trade secret.
對,他還是混蛋一個
Yeah, well, he's still an asshole.
他今天救了你一命
He saved your life today.
相信我,迷宮是危險的地方
Trust me. The maze is a dangerous place.
我們被困在這裡了吧?
We're trapped here, aren't we?
目前是
For the moment.
不過...
But...
你看到這些人嗎?
you see those guys?
火旁邊的人?
There, by the fire?
他們是飛毛腿
Those are the runners.
中間那個是米諾
That guy in the middle there, that's Minho.
他是飛毛腿的小隊長
He's the Keeper of the Runners.
每天早上這些門開啟後
Every morning, when those doors open, they run the maze...
他們會進迷宮
mapping it, memorizing it,
畫地圖、記下來,試著找路離開
trying to find a way out.
他們找多久了?
How long have they been looking?
三年了
Three years.
他們什麼都沒發現嗎?
And they haven't found anything?
說比做容易多了
It's a lot easier said than done.
仔細聽
Listen.
聽到了嗎?
Hear that?
迷宮一直在變化
It's the maze, changing.
每天晚上都會改變
It changes every night.
怎麼可能?
How is that even possible?
去問把我們放在這裡的人啊
You can ask the people who put us in here,
如果你能見到那些混蛋的話
if you ever meet the bastards.
聽著,事實上
Listen, the truth is...
只有飛毛腿知道外面有什麼
the runners are the only ones who really know what's out there.
他們是我們當中最壯最快的人
They are the strongest and the fastest of us all.
這也是好事
And it's a good thing, too...
如果他們在門關上前沒回來
because if they don't make it back before those doors close...
晚上就會困在那裡
then they are stuck out there for the night.
從沒有人能夠在迷宮內活過一晚
And no one has ever survived a night in the maze.
他們會怎樣?
What happens to them?
我們叫它們鬼火獸
Well, we call them Grievers.
當然,沒人看過後還能活著說出來
Of course, no one's ever seen one and lived to tell about it.
但迷宮裡有鬼火獸
But they're out there.
好了,你今晚問夠了
Right, that's enough questions for one night.
走吧
Come on.
你可是貴賓
You're supposed to be the guest of honor.
不,來吧,我帶你去參觀
Oh, no... No! No, come on. Let me show you around.
來吧
Come on.
那是土木手
And there we got the builders.
他們的手很巧
They're very good with their hands...
但腦袋空空
but not a lot going on upstairs.
那是溫斯頓
And then we got Winston...
他是開膛手的小隊長
he's the Keeper of the Slicers.
我們有兩個醫療手,科林特跟傑夫
And we got two med-jacks, Clint and Jeff.
- 怎麼樣?  - 紐特
- Hey, what's up?   - Yo, Newt.
他們大部分時間都在替開膛手包紮
They spend most of their time bandaging up the slicers.
如果我想當飛毛腿呢?
What if I want to be a runner?
我剛剛說的話你有聽進去嗎?
Have you listened to a word I've just said?
沒人想當飛毛腿
No one wants to be a runner.
況且,你得被選上才行
And, besides, you gotta get chosen.
被誰選上?
Chosen by who?
菜鳥,怎麼樣?
What do you say, Greenie?
想讓大家看看你的本事嗎?
Wanna see what you're made of?
菜鳥!菜鳥!菜鳥!
Greenie! Greenie! Greenie!
好
Okay. All right.
菜鳥,規則很簡單
The rules are simple, Greenie.
我想辦法把你推出圈外
I try to push you out of the circle...
你想辦法撐過5秒就行了
you try to last more than five seconds.
別對菜鳥下手太重
Take it easy on the Greenie.
準備好了嗎?
Ready?
起來吧
Get up, boy.
菜鳥,來吧,我跟你還沒完
Come on, Greenie. We're not done yet.
別再叫我菜鳥了
Stop calling me Greenie.
別再叫你菜鳥?
Stop calling you that?
你想要叫啥?遜客?
What do you wanna be called? Shank?
你們覺得咧?他看來像遜客嗎?
What do you think, boys? Does he look like a Shank?
好慘
Come on!
你知道嗎?我決定叫你遜客了
You know what? I think I've settled on Shank.
菜鳥,幹得好
There you go, Greenie!
以菜鳥來說還不賴吧?
Not bad for a Greenie, huh?
湯瑪斯
Thomas.
Thomas. Hey!
湯瑪斯
Thomas!
我想起我的名字了,我叫湯瑪斯
I remember my name. I'm Thomas!
湯瑪斯
Thomas!
湯瑪斯,歡迎你回家
Welcome home, Thomas.
好樣的,湯瑪斯
Good job... Thomas.
那是什麼?
What the hell was that?
朋友,那是鬼火獸
That, my friend, was a Griever.
別擔心,你跟我們在一起很安全
Don't worry, you're safe here with us.
什麼都過不了那些牆
Nothing gets through those walls.
好了,各位
All right, guys.
睡覺去吧,走
Let's tuck it in for the night. Come on.
今天晚上很棒
It was a good night.
幹得好
Good job, man.
你跟我們在一起很安全
You're safe here with us.
WICKED很好
Wicked is good.
外面是什麼?
What's out there?
湯瑪斯...
Thomas, Thomas.
你聽得到我說話嗎?
Can you hear me?
一切即將改變
Everything is going to change.
湯瑪斯
Thomas.
跟我來
Shh.
這裡很平靜吧?
Follow me.
我知道這很難讓人相信
It's peaceful, isn't it?
但以前可不是這樣
I know it's hard to believe, but it wasn't always this way.
我們有過黑暗的日子
We had dark days.
我們因為恐懼失去很多男孩
We lost a lot of boys to fear.
還有恐慌
To panic.
我們進步了很多
We've come far since then.
建立秩序
Established order...
締造和平
made peace.
你跟我說這些幹嘛?
Yeah. Why are you telling me this?
你與眾不同
Because you're not like the others.
充滿好奇心
You're curious.
但你是我們的一員了
But you're one of us now.
你得知道這是什麼意義
You need to know what that means.
他們怎麼了?
What happened to them?
就像我說的
Like I said...
黑暗的日子,湯瑪斯
dark days, Thomas.
有人試過爬上去嗎?
Has anyone tried climbing to the top?
試過了,藤蔓沒有到最上面
Tried it. The ivy doesn't go all the way to the top.
況且,上去後要去哪?
And besides, where are you gonna go from there?
那箱子呢?下次升上來時...
And what about the Box? You know, next time it comes up...
沒用,我們試過了
No, we tried that.
有人在裡面箱子就不會下去
The Box won't go back down with someone in it.
- 那如果...  - 我們試過了,好嗎?
- Okay, what if we...   - No, we tried it, all right?
試了兩次
Twice.
好嗎?相信我
All right? Trust me.
你想得到的我們都試過了
Anything you think of, we've already tried.
只有穿過迷宮才能出去
The only way out of here is through the maze.
聽著,你想幫忙嗎?
Now, look, you wanna be helpful?
去多挖點肥料給我們
Go dig us up some more fertilizer.
"湯瑪斯,拿肥料就對了"
"Just get the fertilizer, Thomas."
"你們確定我幫不上別的忙嗎?"
"Are you sure, guys? I can't help in any other way?"
"不用,拿肥料就好了"
"No, just get the fertilizer.
"你知道在哪,就在樹林中央"
"You know where it is. It's just out in the middle of the woods."
你是本,對嗎?
You're Ben, right?
我們見過面嗎...
I don't know if we ever...
你沒事吧?
Are you okay?
放開我
Get the hell off me!
都是你的錯
It's your fault.
我看到你了
I saw you.
這是你害的
You did this.
我看到你了!
I saw you!
救命啊
Help!
救命,救命啊
Help! Help!
救命啊!
Help!
我要殺了你!
I'll kill you!
把他壓住
Hold him down.
你在幹嘛?
What are you doing?
本,冷靜點
Calm down, Ben.
發生什麼事了?
What the hell happened?
- 他剛剛攻擊我  - 你沒事吧?
- He just attacked me!   - Are you okay?
本,冷靜
Calm down, Ben.
不...
No. No.
拉開他的衣服
All right, lift his shirt.
拉開他的衣服!
Lift his shirt.
不!不!不要...
No! No! Please. Please.
他被螫了
He's been stung.
在大白天被螫?
In the middle of the day?
拜託救救我
Help me, please.
拜託
Please.
拜託,救救我
Please, just help.
把他關進大籠子
Put him in the pit.
大家來幫忙,帶他進大籠子
Everybody, help. Take him to the pit.
- 不!  - 醫療手
- No!   - Med-jack!
拜託別這麼做
Please don't do it!
本,冷靜
Calm down, Ben.
本,好了
Back down, Ben.
聽我說,拜託!
Listen to me! Please!
拜託住手
Please, stop, please!
這是他害的
He did this!
拜託住手,不,拜託救救我
Please stop! No! No, please! Help me!
他到底怎麼了?
So what happened to him?
這叫轉化
It's called "The Changing."
人被螫就會這樣
It's what happens when someone gets stung.
聽好
Listen.
本被螫以後話就說不清楚了
We haven't been able to get a clear word out of Ben since it happened.
他說的話完全沒道理
He's not making any sense.
情況只會愈來愈糟
And it's only gonna get worse.
感染擴散了,他很危險
The infection is spreading. He's dangerous.
他跟你說了什麼?
What did he say to you?
他說他看到我了...
He said he saw me...
這都是我的錯
and that this was all my fault.
這怎麼會是我的錯?
How could this be my fault?
休息一下吧
Get some rest.
- 艾爾比  - 什麼事?
- Alby?   - Yeah.
他會怎麼樣?
What's gonna happen to him?
聽我說,拜託你聽我說
Just listen to me. Just, please, listen to me!
米諾,拜託
Please, Minho!
艾爾比
Alby!
拜託不要
No, please. Please, don't.
拜託別這麼做
Please, don't do it.
竿子
Poles!
往前
Move in!
拜託不要
No, no, no! Please!
拜託不要,拜託,不要
No, please! Please, don't!
我會變好,拜託聽我說
I can get better! Please, just listen to me!
拜託,住手,拜託
Please, stop, please!
- 把他推進去  - 住手
- Push him in!   - Stop!
我會變好
I'll get better!
他現在屬於迷宮了
He belongs to the maze now.
你覺得他熬得過嗎?
Do you think he might make it?
本?
Ben?
不會
No.
沒人在迷宮熬得過一晚
No one survives a night in the maze.
我們只能把他忘了
We just gotta forget about him.
湯瑪斯
Thomas.
WICKED很好
Wicked is good.
別讓他們太輕鬆了
Don't make it easy on them.
湯瑪斯
Thomas.
一切即將改變
Everything is going to change.
WICKED很好
Wicked is good.
這會有點痛
This is gonna hurt a little.
WICKED很好
Wicked is good.
湯瑪斯,你必須抉擇
Thomas, you have to choose.
艾爾比為什麼要進迷宮?
But why would Alby go into the maze?
他又不是飛毛腿
I mean, he's not a runner.
情況不一樣了
Things are different now.
艾爾比在日落前要回溯本的路線
Alby went to retrace Ben's footsteps before sundown.
你要幫忙嗎?
Are you gonna help?
所以他要去本被螫的地方...
So he's gonna go back to where Ben was just stung...
艾爾比清楚自己在做什麼
Alby knows what he's doing...
好嗎?
all right?
他比我們都要清楚
He knows better than any of us.
這是什麼意思?
What does that mean?
事情就像你聽到的
Well, it's like you have heard, yeah?
每個月,箱子會送一個新人上來
Every month, the Box sends up a new arrival.
但總有人是第一個,對嗎?
But someone had to be first, right?
總有人得在迷宮幽地獨自待一個月
Someone had to have spent a whole month in the Glade, alone.
那個人就是艾爾比
That was Alby.
那一定很辛苦
I mean, it can't have been easy.
但其他男孩開始一個接一個出現後
But when those other boys started coming up, one after the other...
他看清楚事實了
he saw the truth.
他發現最重要的事
And he learned that the most important thing...
就是我們擁有彼此
is that we all have each other.
因為我們全都一起捲進這件事了
Because we're all in this together.
對
Yeah.
菜鳥,好樣的
There you go, Greenie.
他們現在應該要回來了
They should be back by now.
萬一他們沒回來呢?
What happens if they don't make it?
他們會回來的
They're gonna make it.
萬一他們沒回來會怎樣?
What happens if they don't?
他們會回來的
They're gonna make it.
拜託,我們不能派人去找他們嗎?
Come on, guys, can't we send someone after them?
這樣違反規定
That's against the rules.
他們要嘛回來,要嘛回不來
Either they make it back or they don't.
我們不能冒險再失去人了
We can't risk losing anyone else.
那裡!
There!
等等,事情不對勁
Wait, something's wrong.
米諾,快點,你可以的
Come on, Minho, you can do it!
快啊
Come on! Go!
快點,你趕得及的
Come on, you can make it!
米諾,你得丟下他
Minho, you gotta leave him!
他們來不及了
They're not gonna make it.
你得丟下他
You gotta leave him!
湯瑪斯,不!
Thomas, no!
幹得好
Good job.
你剛剛害死自己了
You just killed yourself.
什麼?
What?
他怎麼了?
What happened to him?
他看來像怎麼了?
What does it look like?
他被螫了
He got stung.
他的頭怎麼了?
What happened to his head?
我做了該做的事
I did what I had to do.
好,幫我拉他起來
Okay. Okay, help me get him up.
我們得走了,迷宮已經在變化了
We gotta go. The maze is already changing.
米諾!
Hey, Minho!
我們不能把他丟在這裡
We can't just leave him here.
我們得拉他起來
We gotta get him up.
快點
Come on.
讓他坐下來
Just sit him down. Sit him down.
這樣行不通,我們得走了
This isn't going to work. We gotta go.
我們得走了!
We gotta go!
等等,你在說什麼?我們得把他藏起來
Wait, what are you talking about? We gotta hide him.
- 藏在哪裡?  - 我不知道
- Where?   - I don't know.
你是說我們哪裡都不能帶他去嗎?
Are you telling me there's not a single place we could take him?
瞎卡,聽我說
Listen to me, shuck-face, all right.
看看四周,這裡沒有地方去
Take a look around. There's nowhere to go!
你不懂
You don't get it.
我們等於死了
We're already dead.
二、三
Two, three...
好
Okay.
你在幹嘛?你在幹嘛?
What are you doing? What are you doing?
你在幹嘛?
What are you doing?
我們得走了,現在就得走了
We gotta go. We gotta go now!
不,再一點點,然後綁好
No, no, just a little more and we'll tie it off.
米諾,再一下子
Minho, stay with me.
米諾,加油啊
Stay with me, Minho.
再一點點就好,我們快好了
Just a little more, we're almost there.
- 菜鳥,對不起  - 怎麼了?
- I'm sorry, Greenie.   - What?
米諾!
Minho!
好
Okay.
快點
Come on.
靠
Oh, shit!
你這個瘋子
You're a crazy son of a bitch.
快點,跟我來,快點!
Come on, follow me. Come on!
好,迷宮在變化了,快點
Okay, it's changing. Come on, come on!
這一區要關閉了,來吧
This section is closing. Come on.
我們在這裡能甩掉鬼火獸
We can lose it down here!
湯瑪斯!
Thomas!
你還在等什麼?快離開
What are you waiting for? Get out of there!
來吧
Come on!
來吧!
快點,湯瑪斯,不要回頭
Come on, Thomas! Don't look back!
快跑!
Run!
快走,湯瑪斯,快跑啊
Move it, Thomas! Go on!
快動作,走了,快點
Move your ass! Let's go! Come on!
來吧,菜鳥,走了
Come on, Greenie! Let's go!
湯瑪斯!
Thomas!
大家過來
Guys, get up!
查克,我告訴過你了
I told you, Chuck.
他們不會回來了
They're not coming back.
走吧
Let's go.
不會吧
No way.
我抓住他了
I got him, I got him, I got him.
注意,小心
Watch out. Easy.
裡面發生什麼事了?
What happened out there?
你們怎麼出來的?
How did you guys make it out?
你看到鬼火獸了?
You saw a Griever?
對,我看到一隻了
Yeah, I saw one.
他不只是看到
He didn't just see it.
他殺死鬼火獸了
He killed it.
情況起了變化
Things are changing.
這一點不能否認
There's no denying that.
首先,本在大白天被螫
First, Ben gets stung in broad daylight.
接著是艾爾比
And then Alby.
現在,我們的菜鳥接下責任
And now our Greenie, here, has taken it upon himself...
進了迷宮
to go into the maze.
這明顯違反我們的規定
Which is a clear violation of our rules here.
對...
Yeah...
可是他救了艾爾比一命
but he saved Alby's life.
是嗎?
Did he?
三年來,我們跟鬼火獸和平共存
For 3 years, we have coexisted with these things.
現在,你殺了一隻鬼火獸
And now, you've killed one of them.
誰知道這對我們代表什麼意義
Who knows what that could mean for us.
你建議我們該怎麼做?
What do you suggest we do?
他必須受到處罰
He has to be punished.
- 拜託  - 他殺了一隻鬼火獸耶
- Come on.   - He killed a Griever!
米諾
Minho.
你跟他一起進了迷宮,你怎麼想?
You were there with him. What do you think?
我想...
I think...
我們在這裡待了這麼久
in all the time we've been here...
沒有人殺死過鬼火獸
no one has ever killed a Griever before.
我轉身落跑時
When I turned tail and ran...
這個蠢遜客留下來救艾爾比
this dumb shank stayed behind to help Alby.
我不知道他是勇敢還是蠢
Look, I don't know if he's brave or stupid.
但不管是什麼,都是我們需要的
But whatever it is, we need more of it.
我們就讓他當飛毛腿吧
I say we make him a runner.
飛毛腿?什麼?
A runner? What?
米諾,先別急
Minho, let's not jump the gun, here.
湯瑪斯!
Thomas! Thomas! Thomas!
你們要替菜鳥歡呼,沒關係
If you want to throw the newbie a parade, that's fine.
儘管歡呼
Go ahead.
但我很瞭解迷宮的一點
But if there is one thing I know about the maze...
那就是你不能...
it is that you do not...
好,等等,我認得那個聲音
Okay, wait. I know that sound.
- 箱子又上來了  - 怎麼可能
- The Box. It's coming back up.   - It shouldn't be.
紐特,你看到什麼?
Newt, what do you see?
你有看到嗎?
Do you see it?
是個女的
It's a girl.
怎麼可能
No way.
我覺得她死了
I think she's dead.
她手上拿了什麼?
What's in her hand?
"她是最後一個"
"She's the last one... ever."
這是什麼鬼意思?
What the hell does that mean?
湯瑪斯...
Thomas...
你們還是覺得我反應過度嗎?
Do you still think I'm overreacting?
傑夫,怎麼回事?
Jeff, what's going on?
她是怎麼了?她為何醒不過來?
What's the matter with her? Why won't she wake up?
你問我該問誰?
Hey man, I got my job the same way you did.
你認得她嗎?
Do you recognize her?
不認得
No.
真的?因為她似乎認得你
Really? Because she seemed to recognize you.
紙條的事呢?
What about the note?
晚點再來擔心紙條的事
We'll worry about the note later.
我認為你應該現在擔心
I think you should worry about it now.
我們現在要處理的事已經夠多了
We've got enough to deal with at the moment.
紐特,他說的對
He's right, Newt.
如果箱子不再上來了
If the Box isn't coming back up,
你覺得我們能撐多久?
how long do you think we can last?
沒人說箱子不會上來了
No one said that.
先別亂下結論
Let's not jump to any conclusions.
我們等她醒來,瞭解她知道什麼後再說
We'll just wait until she wakes up and see what she knows.
一定有人知道答案
Somebody has gotta have some answers around here.
好
Okay.
- 你要去哪?  - 回去迷宮
- Where are you going?   - Back into the maze.
湯瑪斯
Hey, Thomas.
你是怎麼了?想找死嗎?
What is this with you, huh? A death wish?
你才剛出來就想回去?
You just got out and now you want back in?
紐特說沒人看過鬼火獸後
Newt said that no one has ever seen a Griever
還能活著聊鬼火獸嗎?
and lived to tell about it, right?
米諾,我們現在有一個了
Minho, now we have one.
你是說你一點都不好奇嗎?
You're telling me you're not even a little bit curious?
並沒有
Not really, no.
你有什麼計畫?
So, what's the plan?
你要去靠自己支解鬼火獸嗎?
You're gonna go out and dissect that thing all by yourself?
必要的話,我會
I will if I have to.
其他的飛毛腿離開了嗎?
Have the other runners left yet?
其他的飛毛腿今天早上都不幹了
The other runners quit this morning.
艾爾比被螫後
After Alby got stung, they're not
他們不急著回迷宮
in any hurry to get back out there.
你為何急著回去?
Why are you?
我覺得我們也該瞭解我們面對的到底是什麼了
I think it's time we find out what we're really up against.
好吧
All right.
但你不能獨自回迷宮
But you're not going back out there alone.
半小時後到樹林找我
Meet me in the woods in half-an-hour.
這樣夠嗎?
Will this be enough?
好
Okay.
走吧
Let's go.
快點
Come on!
好噁心
That's disgusting.
裡面有東西
There's something in there.
你是說除了鬼火獸松餅以外嗎?
You mean, besides a Griever pancake?
你在幹嘛?
Whoa, what are you doing?
你不是說它死了嗎?
I thought you said it was dead.
- 是反射動作嗎?  - 最好是啦
- Was it a reflex?   - You hope.
來吧,想辦法把它拔出來吧
Okay, come on. Let's try and pull it out.
大家一起出力,來吧
Everyone get a hand on it. Come on.
準備好了嗎?數到三來
All right, ready? On three.
一、二、三
One, two, three!
- 煎鍋,你沒事吧?  - 沒事,謝了,兄弟
- Are you okay, Fry?   - Yeah. Thanks, brother.
那是什麼鬼東西?
What the hell is that?
有意思
Interesting.
好,不管那是什麼
Okay, whatever it is...
我們能回迷宮幽地再討論嗎?
can we take this up back at the Glade?
因為我可不想看到這傢伙的朋友
Because I don't want to meet this guy's friends.
他說的對
He's right.
時間晚了,走吧
It's getting late. Come on.
我們找到這個
We found this.
它在鬼火獸的體內
It was inside a Griever.
- 我們的物資上有一樣的字  - 對
- These are the same letters we get in our supplies.   - Yeah.
把我們放在這裡的人
Whoever put us here obviously made the Grievers.
顯然創造了鬼火獸
This is the first real clue,
這是第一條真線索,三年多來第一次有收穫
the first anything, you've found in over 3 years.
米諾,對嗎?
Right, Minho?
對
Right.
紐特,我們得回迷宮
Newt, we gotta go back out there.
誰知道這能讓我們找到什麼
Who knows where this might lead us.
你知道他想幹嘛,對嗎?
You see what he's trying to do, right?
先是破壞我們的規定
First he breaks our rules...
然後說服我們完全放棄規定
and then he tries to convince us to abandon them totally.
只有規定能讓大家凝聚在一起
The rules are the only thing that have ever held us together.
我們現在為何要質疑這一點?
Why now are we questioning that?
如果艾爾比在這裡,你知道他會同意我的話
If Alby was here, you know he'd agree with me.
這個遜客必須受罰
This shank needs to be punished.
說的對
You're right.
湯瑪斯是打破規定
Thomas broke the rules.
把他關進大籠子一晚,不准吃飯
One night in the pit, and no food.
拜託,紐特,關進大籠子一晚?
Come on, Newt! One night in the pit?
你覺得這會阻止他進迷宮嗎?
Do you think that's gonna stop him from going into the maze?
不會
No.
我們不能讓非飛毛腿想去迷宮就去
And we can't just have non-runners running into the maze whenever they feel like it.
我們正式搞定這件事吧
So let's just make this official.
從明天起,你就是飛毛腿了
Starting from tomorrow, you're a runner.
- 蓋裡...  - 煎鍋,別說了
- Gally...   -  No, Fry.
紐特,謝了
Thanks, Newt.
我們要去哪?
Hey, where are we going?
你待會就知道了
You'll see.
這是迷宮
It's the maze.
整座迷宮
All of it.
整座迷宮是啥意思?你們不是還在畫地圖嗎?
What do you mean "all of it"? I thought you were still mapping it.
沒有東西可以畫了
There's nothing left to map.
我親自把每一寸都跑遍了
I've run every inch of it myself.
每個迴圈
Every cycle.
每個模式都是
Every pattern.
如果有出路,我們早就找到了
If there was a way out, we would have found it by now.
你為何沒跟任何人說這件事?
Why haven't you told anyone this?
這是艾爾比的決定
It was Alby's call.
大家必須相信我們有機會離開
People needed to believe we had a chance of getting out.
但或許現在...
But maybe now...
我們是真的有機會了
we have a real chance.
你看一下這個
Take a look at this.
一年前,我們開始探索這些週邊的區
About a year ago, we started exploring these outer sections.
我們發現牆上印了這些號碼
We found these numbers printed on the walls.
第一區到第八區
Sections 1 through 8.
它的運作方式是每天晚上
See, the way it works,
迷宮起變化時
is every night, when the maze changes...
會打開一個新的區
it opens up a new section.
所以今天打開的是第六區
So today, Section 6 was open.
明天是第四區,接著是第八區,然後是第三區
Tomorrow, it will be 4, then 8, then 3.
模式永遠不變
The pattern always stays the same.
第七區哪裡特別了?
What's so special about 7?
我不知道
I don't know.
但昨晚,在你殺死那只鬼火獸時
But last night, when you killed that Griever...
第七區開啟了
Section 7 was open.
我認為鬼火獸一定從那裡來
I think it must be where it comes from.
明天,你跟我要過去了解
Tomorrow, you and I are gonna take a closer look.
你們在幹嘛?你們不准進來的
What are you guys doing? You're not allowed in here.
- 抱歉,是...  - 是那女孩
- Sorry, it's just the, uh...   - It's the girl.
她醒了嗎?
Is she awake?
可以這麼說
You could say that.
查克,怎麼回事?
Chuck, what's going on?
女孩有夠棒
Girls are awesome.
別煩我
Leave me alone!
小心頭
Watch your head!
喂,你再丟石頭...
Hey, throw one more of those things... Ow!
- 走開  - 我們沒有惡意
- Go away!   - We come in peace!
- 發生什麼事了?  - 快閃
- What happened?   - Just duck!
我覺得她不太喜歡我們
I don't think she likes us very much.
- 你們想怎樣?  - 我們只想談談
- What do you want from me?   - We just wanna talk.
我警告你們喔
I'm warning you!
大家快找掩護!
Take cover, y'all! Take cover!
我是湯瑪斯!
Hey, it's Thomas! It's Thomas!
我要上去,好嗎?
I'm gonna come up, okay?
好
Okay.
就我一個
Just me.
我上來了
I'm coming up.
好,就...
Okay, just...
別激動,好嗎?
Easy, all right?
我在哪裡?
Where am I?
這是什麼地方?
What is this place?
我為何什麼都記不得了?
Why can't I remember anything?
這都很正常,好嗎?我們全都經歷過
This is all normal. Okay? We've all been through this.
好嗎?
Okay?
你過兩天就會想起你的名字
Your name will come back to you in a couple of days.
- 這件事...  - 特蕾莎
- It's the one thing that...   - Teresa.
你說什麼?
What did you say?
我的名字
My name.
我叫特蕾莎
It's Teresa.
特蕾莎,我是湯瑪斯
Teresa, I'm Thomas.
但我猜你已經知道了吧?
But you already knew that, though, I guess, huh?
他們說我在睡夢中一直喊你的名字
They said I kept saying your name in my sleep.
你是誰?
Who are you?
我不知道
I don't know.
我不記得了
I can't remember.
這裡的人都想不起任何事情
None of us here can remember anything.
我們都像你一樣醒來就在這裡了
We all woke up here just like you did.
我保證...
Hey, I promise...
我要把刀拿走
I'm gonna take this.
好
Okay.
上面情況怎麼樣?
What's going on up there?
她要下來嗎?
Is she coming down?
等我們一下,好嗎?
Hey, listen, you guys just give us a second, okay?
好
All right.
走吧
Come on.
女生都這樣嗎?
Is this what all girls are like?
這女的瘋了
That girl is crazy.
"她是最後一個",這是什麼意思?
"She's the last one." What does that mean?
我不確定
I'm not sure.
但你上來後,箱子就沒下去了
Ever since you came up, that Box hasn't gone back down.
我想這讓大家有點擔心
I just think it's got everyone a little worried.
尤其是蓋裡
Especially Gally.
他認為這是我的錯
He thinks it's my fault.
你確定你不記得任何其他的事?
Are you sure you don't remember anything else?
我記得水...
I remember water...
感覺就像我溺水了
feeling like I was drowning.
那些臉孔直盯著我看
These faces staring at me.
一個女人的聲音說著重複的事
And this woman's voice saying the same thing over and over.
WICKED很好
"Wicked is good."
自從我來這裡後,我就做著這些夢
Ever since I've been here, I've had these dreams.
我以為那是夢
Well, I thought they were dreams.
你...
You...
你在我的夢裡
You were there.
你在夢裡...
You were there...
你告訴我一切即將改變
and you told me that everything was gonna change.
這是什麼意思?
What does it mean?
我不知道,我只有夢到片段
I don't know. I just always get pieces.
其他人什麼都不記得嗎?
And the others don't remember anything?
不記得
No.
我們為什麼不一樣?
Why are we different?
我上來時口袋裡放了這個
These were in my pocket when I came up.
"WICKED很好"
"Wicked is good."
要是我們被送來這裡是有理由的呢?
What if we were sent here for a reason?
艾爾比
Alby.
我們甚至不知道這東西是啥
We don't even know what this stuff is.
我們不知道是誰送來的
We don't know who sent it.
也不知道這為什麼跟你一起上來
Or why it came up here with you.
我們只知道,這東西可能害他沒命
For all we know, this thing could kill him.
他已經快沒命了
He's already dying.
看看他
Look at him.
情況不可能更糟了
How could this possibly make it any worse?
快點,這值得一試
Come on, it's worth a try.
好吧
All right.
動手吧
Do it.
好
Okay.
你不應該在這裡的!
You shouldn't be here! You shouldn't be here!
不!
No!
小心
Watch out!
拿針筒,放手
Get the syringe! Let go!
有效了
Well, that worked.
好,從現在開始
Okay, from now on...
讓一個人留下來全天候看著他
someone stays here and watches him around the clock.
菜鳥,天黑了,走吧
Sundown, Greenie. Time to go.
你對我到底有什麼意見?
Hey, what is your problem with me?
當你出現後一切都變了
Everything started going wrong the minute you showed up.
先是本,接著是艾爾比
First Ben, then Alby...
現在是那女孩
and now the girl.
大家都看到她認得你了
Everybody saw she recognized you.
我敢說你知道她是誰
And I'm betting you know who she is.
蓋裡
Gally...
你知道我們不能永遠待在這裡吧?
you know we can't stay here forever, right?
誰在那裡?
Who's there?
是我啦
It's just me.
查克,抱歉
Sorry, Chuck.
來
Here.
吃飽了比較有力氣
You'll run better on a full stomach.
查克,謝了
Thanks, Chuck.
那是什麼?
Hey, what do you got there?
刻得挺好的
Wow, that came out pretty damn good.
這是幹嘛用的?
What's that for?
要送給我爸媽的
It's for my parents.
你記得你的爸媽?
You remember your parents?
不記得
No.
我是說,我知道我一定有爸媽
I mean, I know I must have them.
不管他們在哪,我相信他們很想我
And wherever they are, I'm sure they miss me...
但我沒辦法想念他們,因為我不記得他們了
but I can't miss them because I don't remember them.
你覺得你明天進迷宮會發現什麼?
What do you think you're gonna find out there tomorrow?
我不知道
Uh, I don't know.
不過查克,如果有出路
But if there's a way out, Chuck,
我跟米諾會找到的
me and Minho are gonna find it.
拿去
Here.
查克,你幹嘛把木雕給我?
Chuck, why would you give this to me?
反正我也不記得他們
I can't remember them anyway.
但如果你找到出路
But maybe if you find a way out,
就能替我交給他們
you can give it to them for me.
睡吧
I'll let you get some sleep.
查克
Hey, Chuck.
過來
Come here.
手伸出來
Put out your hand.
我要你自己交給你爸媽
I want you to give that to them yourself.
我們會離開這裡的
We're gonna get out of here.
全部的人都會
All of us.
好嗎?
Okay?
我保證
I promise.
- 好  - 好
- Yeah.   - All right.
- 晚安  - 兄弟,晚安
- Good night.   - Good night, buddy.
菜鳥,今天是大日子
Big day, Greenie.
你確定你不要跳過?
Are you sure you don't wanna sit this one out?
- 拜託,讓我出去吧  - 好
- Come on, man. Get me out of here.   - All right.
走吧
Let's go!
往這裡,內圈快到了
This way. Not much further to the inner ring.
走吧
Let's go!
快點,走這裡
Come on! This way.
奇怪
That's strange.
怎麼了?
What?
第七區應該下禮拜才會開
Seven is not supposed to be open for another week.
這是什麼鬼地方?
What the hell is this place?
我們叫它們刀片
We call them blades.
這是本的上衣吧?
It's Ben's, isn't it?
對
Yeah.
一隻鬼火獸一定把他拖到這裡了
A Griever must have pulled him down here.
我覺得它在指引我們方向
I think it's showing us the way.
- 等等...  - 幹嘛?
- Wait, wait, wait.   - What, what?
這裡,走
This way. Come on.
米諾,你看過這個地方嗎?
Minho, you ever see this place before?
沒有
No.
這只是另一條死路
It's just another dead end.
你確定要進去嗎?
Are you sure about this?
不確定
Nope.
鬼火獸
Grievers.
那是什麼鬼?
What the hell was that?
我們得離開這裡
We gotta get out of here.
把鑰匙給我
Give me the key, give me the key!
快跑
Move, move!
我們得走了,湯瑪斯,快跑
We gotta go! Run, Thomas!
我們會被困住
We're gonna get trapped!
快走
Go! Go!
快走...
Go, go, go!
快跑
Move!
米諾!
Minho!
快點,快走...
Come on! Let's go, let's go!
快點跑!
Come on, move!
繼續跑,快走
Keep going! Keep going! Let's go!
快走...
Go, go, go!
快點,別回頭
Come on! Don't look back!
快啊!
Come on!
靠
Oh, shit!
往那裡
There! Whoa, whoa, whoa!
剛剛發生什麼事了?
What the hell's going on out there?
湯瑪斯,你又幹了什麼好事了?
What the hell you done now, Thomas?
我們發現一條新的通道
We found something, a new passage.
我們認為那可能是出路
We think it could be a way out.
- 真的嗎?  - 這是真的
- Really?   - It's true.
我們開啟一扇門,看到我從來沒看過的東西
We opened a door, something I'd never seen before.
我認為鬼火獸白天一定躲在那裡
I think it must be where the Grievers go during the day.
等等!
Wait! Whoa, whoa, whoa...
你是說你們找到鬼火獸的巢穴了?
You're saying you found the Grievers' home?
而且你們想要我們進去?
And you want us to go in?
它們進迷宮的路可能是我們的出路
Their way in could be our way out, Chuck.
對,另一邊也可能有十幾隻鬼火獸
Yeah, or there could be a dozen Grievers on the other side.
事實是湯瑪斯不知道自己在幹嘛,又來了
The truth is, Thomas doesn't know what he has done, as usual.
蓋裡,起碼我有做事
Yeah, at least I did something, Gally.
你做過什麼事了?
I mean, what have you done?
你只會一直躲在牆後
Aside from hide behind these walls all the time?
菜鳥,讓我告訴你一件事
Let me tell you something, Greenie.
你才來三天,好嗎?我來三年了
You've been here 3 days, all right? I've been here 3 years!
對,你來三年了,現在還在這裡
Yeah, you've been here 3 years and you're still here, Gally!
這告訴了你什麼?
What does that tell you?
或許你該開始改變做法了
Maybe you should start doing things a little differently.
或許你該主事,如何?
Maybe you should be in charge, what about that?
是艾爾比
Hey, it's Alby!
他醒了
He's awake.
他有說什麼嗎?
Has he said anything?
沒有
No.
艾爾比
Alby...
艾爾比,你還好嗎?
Alby, are you all right?
艾爾比
Hey, Alby.
艾爾比,我們可能找到離開迷宮的路了
Alby, we might have just found a way out of the maze.
你聽到我說話了嗎?我們可以離開了
Do you hear me? We could be getting out of here.
我們不能
We can't.
我們走不了
We can't leave.
他們不會讓我們走的
They won't let us.
你在說什麼?
What are you talking about?
我想起來了
I remember.
你想起來什麼了?
What do you remember?
你
You.
湯瑪斯,你一向是他們的最愛
You were always their favorite, Thomas.
一向都是
Always.
你為什麼要這麼做?
Why did you do this?
你為什麼要來這裡?
Why did you come here?
溫斯頓,怎麼了?
Winston, what's going on?
迷宮的門沒有關閉
It's the doors. They aren't closing.
查克
Chuck,
去議事室把門擋住
go to the Council Hall and start barricading the doors.
- 溫斯頓,你跟他一起去  - 瞭解
- Winston, you go with him.   - Got it.
- 去找其他人  - 叫他們去樹林,快去躲起來
- Get the others.   - Tell them to go to the forest. Go hide, now!
米諾,我要你去拿所有的武器
Minho, I want you to grab every weapon you can find.
- 我跟你在議事室見  - 走
- I'll meet you at Council Hall.   - Let's go.
特蕾莎,你跟我去找艾爾比,好嗎?
Teresa, you and I are gonna go get Alby, all right?
好了,大家躲起來
All right, everybody hide!
特蕾莎!
Teresa!
快點,快跑!
Come on! Run! Run!
蹲低!
Stay down!
快跑
Run!
薩特!
Zart!
- 救救我  - 快去村落
- Help me!   - Go! Get to the village!
快走...
Go, go, go!
蹲低!
Stay down, stay down!
蓋裡,讓我進去
Gally! Let me in, let me in!
- 艾爾比!  - 你沒事吧?
- Alby!   - Are you okay?
怎麼回事?
What's going on?
- 它們來了  - 鬼火獸嗎?
- They're here.   - Grievers?
湯瑪斯,我們該怎麼辦?
Thomas, what do we do?
它螫到我了
It's got me!
大家快跑
Everybody, run, run, run!
傑夫,快點,快走...
Jeff, come on, go, go, go!
大家快走
Everyone, go, go, go!
繼續跑,靠
Keep moving! Oh, shit!
艾爾比
Alby!
躲到我後面
Get behind me!
來啊
Come on!
這裡,走吧
Over here, let's go!
這裡!走吧,來吧
Over here! Let's go! Come on!
這裡,來啊
Over here, come on!
溫斯頓!
Winston!
扶艾爾比進去
Get Alby inside.
查克,進去!快走...
Chuck, get in! Go, go, go!
把門鎖上
Lock down the doors!
小心
Careful.
大家退後
Stay back, guys.
大家都沒事吧?
Is everyone all right?
救命啊
Help!
- 快抓住他  - 救命啊
- Hey, grab him!   - Help!
小心
Watch out!
查克!
Chuck!
- 查克,不!  - 抓住他
- Chuck, no!   - Grab him!
把他拉回來
Pull him back!
- 救命啊  - 查克,別放手
- Help!   - Chuck, don't let go!
廢話
No shit!
- 快拉  - 別放開他
- Pull!   - Don't let him go!
- 查克,你沒事吧?  - 我沒事
- Chuck, are you okay?   - Yeah, I'm fine.
艾爾比,謝了
Thanks, Alby.
艾爾比,小心!
Alby! Watch out!
抓住他
Grab him!
湯瑪斯,帶他們出去
Thomas, get them out.
艾爾比!
Alby!
不!湯瑪斯...
No! Thomas...
- 湯瑪斯!  - 別過去
- Thomas!   - Don't go out there!
不,湯瑪斯,等等!
No, Thomas, wait!
湯瑪斯,等等!
Thomas, wait!
大家去哪了?
Where is everybody?
是誰在那邊?
Who's that over there?
蓋裡...
Gally...
湯瑪斯,都是你害的,看看四周
This is all you, Thomas! Look around!
蓋裡,別過來,這不是湯瑪斯的錯
Back off, Gally! It's not Thomas' fault!
你聽到艾爾比說什麼了
You heard what Alby said!
- 他是他們的一員  - 誰的一員?
- He's one of them!   - One of who?
他是他們的人,他們派他來搞破壞
He's one of them, and they sent him here
這下他成功了
to destroy everything, and now he has!
看看四周,湯瑪斯,看看四周啊
Look around, Thomas! Look around!
這都是你的錯
This is your fault!
蓋裡,別過來,這不是湯瑪斯的錯
Back off, Gally! This is not Thomas' fault!
你在鬼扯什麼?冷靜下來
What are you talking about? Calm down.
他們派他過來
They sent him here,
他現在把我們打造的一切都毀了
and now he's destroyed everything that we've built!
你在鬼扯什麼?
What are you talking about?
或許他說的對
Maybe he's right.
湯瑪斯...
Thomas...
特蕾莎,我得想起過去的事
I need to remember, Teresa.
湯瑪斯...
Thomas...
- 湯瑪斯!  - 不要!
- Thomas!   - No, don't!
湯瑪斯!
Thomas!
查克,拿另一支針筒來
Chuck, get the other syringe!
沒事
It's okay.
湯瑪斯,我在這裡
Thomas, I'm here.
是誰把我們放在這裡的?
Who put us here?
這一點我們不知道
That we don't know.
特蕾莎...
Teresa...
我們為什麼要這麼做?
why are we doing this?
湯瑪斯,很好
Excellent, Thomas.
跟我來
Come with me.
湯瑪斯...
Wicked isn't good. Thomas...
WICKED很好
Wicked is good.
這怎麼會是我的錯?
How could this be my fault?
這是你害的!
You did this!
我看到你了!
I saw you!
我沒辦法一直看著他們沒命
I can't keep watching them die.
你還好嗎?
Are you okay?
你到底在想什麼?
What the hell were you thinking?
發生什麼事了?
What happened?
蓋裡接管這裡了
Gally has taken control.
他說給我們一個選擇,不加入他...
He said we had a choice. Either join him...
就在日落時跟你一起被驅逐
or get banished at sundown with you.
其他人同意這麼做嗎?
And the others agreed to that?
蓋裡說服大家這一切都是你的緣故
Gally has everyone convinced that you're the reason all this has happened.
他到目前為止沒說錯
Well, he's been right so far.
你到底在說什麼?
What are you talking about?
這個地方...
This place...
不是我們以為的那樣
it's not what we thought it was.
這不是監牢,這是測試
It's not a prison, it's a test.
這從我們小時候就開始了
It all started when we were kids.
他們會給我們挑戰
They would give us these challenges.
他們拿我們做實驗
They were experimenting on us.
然後人們開始不見
And then people started disappearing.
每個月,一個接著一個,很規律
Every month, one after the other, like clockwork.
他們把這些人送去迷宮
They were sending them up into the maze.
對,但不是我們全部的人
Yeah, but not all of us.
什麼意思?
What do you mean?
各位,我是他們的一員
Guys, I'm one of them.
我跟把你們放在這裡的人共事
The people who put you here, I worked with them.
我觀察你們好幾年了
I watched you guys for years.
你們在這裡的全部期間...
The entire time you have been here...
我都在另一邊
I was on the other side of it.
你也一樣
So were you.
什麼?
What?
特蕾莎,這是我們做的
Teresa, we did this to them.
不
No.
這不可能是真的
That can't be true.
這是,我看到了
It is. I saw it.
如果我們是同夥,他們為何要送我們上來?
Why would they send us up if we were with them?
不重要
It doesn't matter.
他說的對
He's right.
不重要
It doesn't matter.
這一切都不重要
Any of it.
因為來迷宮前的我們已經不存在了
Because the people we were before the maze don't even exist anymore.
創造者解決掉了
These Creators took care of that.
我們現在是誰才重要
But what does matter is who we are now, and what we do...
我們現在做的事也是
right now.
你進入迷宮找到出路
You went into the maze and you found a way out.
對,但如果我沒去,艾爾比也不會沒命
Yeah, but if I hadn't, Alby would still be alive.
或許吧
Maybe.
但我知道如果他還活著
But I know that if he were here,
他會跟你說一樣的話
he would be telling you the exact same thing.
解決問題,收拾殘局
Pick your ass up and finish what you started.
因為如果我們坐以待斃
Because if we do nothing...
那就表示艾爾比白白犧牲了,我可不容許這種事
then that means Alby died for nothing, and I can't have that.
好
Okay.
好,但我們得先過蓋裡那一關
Okay, but we gotta get through Gally first.
太可惜了
This is such a waste.
蓋裡...
Gally...
驅逐他們感覺不對
It doesn't feel right, man.
萬一湯瑪斯說的是對的呢?
Yeah, what if Thomas is right?
說不定他能帶領我們回家
Maybe he can lead us home.
這裡就是家
We are home.
好嗎?
Okay?
我不想再劃掉牆上任何一個名字了
I don't wanna have to cross any more names off that wall.
你真的認為驅逐我們能解決事情嗎?
You really think banishing us is gonna solve anything?
不
No.
但這不是驅逐
But this isn't a banishing.
這是獻祭
It's an offering.
什麼?等等
What? Wait!
蓋裡,你在幹嘛?
Gally, what are you doing?
你真的以為在湯瑪斯做出那種事後
You really think I'm gonna let Thomas
我會讓他回迷宮嗎?
back into the maze after what he has done?
看看四周
Look around you!
看看我們的迷宮幽地
Look at our Glade!
這是唯一的辦法
This is the only way.
鬼火獸如願後
And when the Grievers get what they came here for...
一切就會恢復以往
everything goes back to the way it was.
你們有在聽嗎?
Are you listening to this?
你們光杵在那裡幹嘛?他瘋了
Why are you all just standing there? He's crazy!
你給我閉嘴
You shut up. If you stay here,
留下來,鬼火獸就會回來
the Grievers are going to come back.
它們會一而再、再而三回來
They're gonna come back, and they're gonna keep coming back...
直到你們全都死光
until you're all dead!
閉嘴,把他綁起來
Shut up! Tie him up!
你們聽到我說話嗎?把他綁起來
Do you hear me? I said tie him up!
你真是充滿驚奇啊
You're full of surprises, aren't you?
你不必跟我們走,但我們要離開了
You don't have to come with us, but we are leaving.
想一起來的人,這是最後的機會
Anyone else who wants to come, now is your last chance.
別聽他的,他只是想嚇唬你們
Don't listen to him, he's just trying to scare you.
我不是想嚇唬你們,你們已經夠害怕了
No, I'm not trying to scare you. You're already scared.
我很害怕
I'm scared.
但我寧可去外面冒險
But I'd rather risk my life out there
也不想在這裡耗一輩子
than spending the rest of it in here.
我們不屬於這個地方
We don't belong here.
這裡不是我們的家
This place isn't our home.
我們被人放在這裡
We were put here.
我們困在這裡
We were trapped here.
起碼,我們在外面還有得選擇
At least, out there we have a choice.
我們出得去
We can make it out of here.
我知道
I know that.
對不起
I'm sorry.
蓋裡,事情結束了
Gally, it's over.
跟我們走吧
Just come with us.
祝你們對抗鬼火獸順利
Good luck against the Grievers.
各位,往這邊
Everybody, this way!
大家跟上,我們就快到了
Keep it up, guys, we're almost there!
- 那是鬼火獸嗎?  - 對
- Is it a Griever?   - Yeah.
靠
Shit.
查克,這你拿著,跟在我們後面
You take this, Chuck. Stay behind us.
沒事,跟緊我就對了
It's okay. Just stick with me.
我們通過後,它就會啟動將門打開
Once we're through, it will activate and the door will open.
我們團結在一起...
We stay close, we stick together...
共度難關,現在就離開...
we get through this. We get out now...
不成功便成仁
or we die trying.
準備好了嗎?
Ready?
好,走吧
All right. Let's go!
起來,小心
Get up, look out!
進逼!
Push it!
小心
Look out!
鑰匙!
The key!
查克!小心邊緣
Chuck! Watch the edge!
- 查克,我罩你  - 拉我上去
- I got you, Chuck!   - Pull me up!
快點
Come on!
湯瑪斯!
Thomas! Thomas!
查克?
Chuck?
又有鬼火獸來了
We got more coming!
大家冷靜
Keep it steady, guys!
有用耶
It works!
特蕾莎,走!
Teresa, go!
- 別往後退,繼續進逼  - 團結在一起
- Don't back down! Keep pushing!   - Stay together!
一定有路可以出去,走吧
There's gotta be a way out! Come on!
小心
Watch it!
門打不開
It won't open!
湯瑪斯! 有密碼
Thomas! There's a code!
八個數字
Eight numbers!
迷宮的八區
Eight sections of the maze.
- 米諾,順序是什麼?  - 什麼?
- Hey, Minho! What's the sequence?   - What?
迷宮那些區的順序是什麼?
The sections of the maze, what's the sequence?
七、一!
Seven! One!
五、二!
Five! Two!
- 六、四!  - 注意了
- Six! Four!   - Heads up!
米諾!
Minho!
Minho! Oh!
放開我!
Get off of me!
傑夫!
Jeff!
順序是什麼?快點?
What's the sequence? Come on!
六、四、八!
Six! Four! Eight!
三!有了嗎?
Three! You got it?
撐住
Keep holding!
快好了,快點
Almost there, come on!
門開了!
The door opened!
真的假的?
Seriously?
這裡發生什麼事了?
What happened here?
他們真的在監視我們
So they were watching us.
從第一天開始
This whole time.
哈羅
Hello.
我是艾娃佩琪博士
My name is Doctor Ava Paige.
我是災後世界狙殺平臺實驗處處長
I'm Director of Operations of the World Catastrophe Killzone Department.
如果你們正在收看
If you're watching this, that means
就表示你們已成功完成迷宮試驗
you have successfully completed the Maze Trials.
我希望我能親自在場恭喜大家
I wish I could be there in person to congratulate you...
但情況似乎不容許
but circumstances seem to have prevented it.
我相信大家現在一定非常困惑
I'm sure by now, you must all be very confused...
憤怒
angry...
害怕
frightened.
我只能向大家擔保,你們所經歷的一切
I can only assure you, that everything that's happened to you...
我們對你們所做的一切
everything we've done to you...
都是有理由的
it was all done for a reason.
你們不會記得
You won't remember...
但太陽烤焦了我們的世界
but the Sun has scorched our world.
幾十億人被大火燒死
Billions of lives lost to fire...
因饑荒而死
famine...
全球飽受苦難
suffering on a global scale.
結果不堪想像
The fallout was unimaginable.
之後的情況更糟
What came after was worse.
我們稱之為閃焰症
We called it the Flare.
這個致命的病毒會侵襲大腦
A deadly virus that attacks the brain.
它劇烈...
It is violent...
不可預期...
unpredictable...
無法治療
incurable.
我們原本以為如此
Or so we thought.
後來,能抵抗病毒的新生代出現
In time, a new generation emerged that could survive the virus.
突然間,人類又燃起治癒的希望
Suddenly, there was a reason to hope for a cure.
但找到治療辦法並不容易
But finding it would not be easy.
年輕人得受到測試、甚至犧牲生命
The young would have to be tested, even sacrificed...
局限在嚴苛的環境內
inside harsh environments...
他們的腦部活動才能接受研究
where their brain activity could be studied.
大家都在努力瞭解
All in an effort to understand...
是什麼讓他們與眾不同...
what makes them different...
是什麼讓你們與眾不同
what makes you different.
你們或許不明白
You may not realize it...
但你們非常重要
but you're very important.
不幸的是,你們的試煉才剛展開
Unfortunately, your trials have only just begun.
你們不久後將發現
As you will no doubt soon discover,
不是人人都同意本處的作法
not everyone agrees with our methods.
進步的過程緩慢,世人很懼怕
Progress is slow, people are scared.
現在對我們或許為時已晚
It may be too late for us...
對我來說太晚
for me...
但對你們來說並不是
but not for you.
外界在等待
The outside world awaits.
別忘了
Remember...
WICKED很好
Wicked is good.
迷宮試驗結束了嗎?
Is it over?
她說我們很重要
She said we were important.
我們現在該怎麼辦?
What are we supposed to do now?
我不知道
I don't know.
我們離開這裡吧
Let's get out of here.
不
No.
- 蓋裡?  - 不要過去
- Gally?   - Don't.
他被螫了
He's been stung.
我們無法離開
We can't leave.
我們離開了,蓋裡,我們出來了
We did. Gally, we're out.
我們自由了
We're free.
自由?
Free?
你認為我們在外面自由嗎?
You think we're free out there?
不
No.
我們無法逃離這個地方的
No, there's no escape from this place.
蓋裡,聽我說
Gally, listen to me.
你腦筋糊塗了
You're not thinking straight.
真的
You're not.
我們可以幫你
Now, we can help you.
把槍放下吧
Just put down the gun.
我屬於迷宮
I belong to the maze.
把槍放下
Just put down the gun.
我們都屬於迷宮
We all do.
湯瑪斯...
Thomas...
查克
Chuck.
靠...
Oh, shit. Shit.
看著我...
Look at me, look at me!
靠
Oh, shit!
查克,看著我,好嗎?
Chuck, look at me, all right?
有我在,兄弟,撐著點
I got you, buddy. Just hang on.
沒事
It's okay.
湯瑪斯...
Thomas, Thomas...
不,查克,你要親自交給你爸媽
No, Chuck. You're gonna give it to them yourself.
記得嗎?我跟你說過了
Remember, I told you that.
拿著
Take it.
不
No.
謝謝
Thank you.
不,查克,你會好的...
No, Chuck, you're gonna get...
查克
Chuck.
查克?
Chuck? Hey.
查克,別這樣
Hey, Chuck, come on!
快點,醒醒啊
Come on, wake up!
天啊
Damn it!
我們逃出來了,別這樣
We made it. Come on.
對不起
I'm sorry!
可惡!
God damn it!
Damn it!
- 湯瑪斯  - 查克
- Thomas.   - Chuck!
查克,起來啊,快點
Get up, Chuck! Come on!
查克!
Chuck!
你們不能把他丟在那裡
You can't just leave him there!
你們沒事吧?
You guys all right?
別擔心
Don't worry.
你們安全了
You're safe now.
(WICKED 基地A)
小子,放輕鬆
Relax, kid.
一切即將改變
Everything is gonna change.
我想我們可以說迷宮試驗大獲成功
I think it's safe to say the Maze Trials were a complete success.
我沒想到會有這麼多人存活,但...
I wasn't expecting so many survivors, but...
人愈多愈好啊
the more the merrier.
湯瑪斯不斷讓人驚豔
Thomas continues to surprise and impress.
目前,他們似乎上鉤了
And for now, they seem to have taken the bait.
現在說可能還太早
It's too soon to say...
但他們可能是一切的關鍵
but they could be the key to everything.
我們繼續吧
So let's move forward.
該展開第二階段了
It's time now to begin Phase Two.